Pokémon Black and White is set in America,
But doesn't feature a Pokémon that looks like a tomahawk missile.
Any other missed opportunities? Yes!
Let me tell you.
[Garbage Guide Intro SFX]
Kilian, why did you pick Pokémon White?
I don't like your accusatory tone.
What?
I, love Pokémon Black.
I have several friends who own Pokémon Black.
I would buy Pokémon Black again, if I could.
I just happen to pick Pokémon White every single time.
The game begins with Pokémon being introduced to us by Professor Juniper.
Who is he?
It's a woman!
I bet you thought only men could be Pokémon professors!
Your world view belongs back in 2009!
It's a new decade now, sexist!
Then we get to pick gender.
Gonna pick a boy this time-- ah...
The DS caught fire.
I really don't know how to play a male character.
Picking name...
Her canonical name is...
HILDA? WAS?
I thought this game was set in Yankyland.
I know every Pokémon game has Germans,
(shows Hiker sprites)
But I would never give my protagonist a German name.
Maybe this time, I won't give her a name.
We'll just call her by the type of Pokémon we will have.
And I was thinking, in this game, I'm gonna focus on wolf-like Pokémons
A gang of wolves; so we'll call her:
WOLFGANG!
[Amadeus movie theme]
"Wolfgaaang!"
[Theme continues]
"I killed her!"
[Villagers chattering]
"Hierr N?"
"Leave me alone."
"I cannot, I have to help your pained soul."
"With the help of the Arceus, the Bidoof, and the holy Ghost-type."
"Do you know who I am?"
"I was a trainer."
"You battle Pokémon?"
"A bit, here in Unova."
"Ah, then you must know this Pokémon."
(shows Boldore)
"Uh, I- can't say that I do."
(shows Arceops)
"Here, how about this one?"
"I... regret, it's not familiar."
"Ah... here, what about this one?"
(shows Eevee)
"Yes! That's Eevee! You trained Eevee?"
"I didn't know that!"
"I didn't."
[silence]
"That..."
"...was Wolfgang!"
Pokémon White begins in Nuvema.
Immediately, we get to pick our Pokémon.
Come on, Gamefreak, let us have a little foreplay!
We also get to meet our rivals immediately.
On the right, I think his name is pronounced, 'Cheren'
It's Bulgarian, he's from the Balkans, so he wants to become Pokémon Champion so he can buy a BMW.
On the left- euhh, not even gonna Google how to pronounce that.(be-ang-ka)
Her father doesn't want her to become a Pokémon trainer,
...and travel to New York alone.
Which, according to this game, makes him a terrible person.
Who to pick...
I don't like any of these.
I'm picking the pig.
Let me be blunt:
In these games, you travel to exotic places,
On oceans.
There is a chance, you get stuck.
And if you starve-, then you'll want the pig!
Without asking, Bianca,
Throws her Pokémon out and attacks me.
Look at my room!
My TV was on before!
You little shit owe me a lot of money!
The three head to Juniper's lab.
She's like:
"Wow, Pokémon have already started to trust you."
"Like I trust my husband!"
"B-But here's a Pokédex!"
"It has a camera!"
"If you see near that 18-year old Ponyta trainer, take a picture!"
Thus the gang can leave for their grand adventure.
Without planning? You people mad?!
I'm going home, to plan out an-
Oh, right. My room.
Impulsive trip it is! Let's go!
Oh god, how did I get back here?
I'm STUCK.
I really should've planned my trip.
I guess I have no choice...
Hey, piggy...
'Tepig!'
(slowly raises gun)
Yes, Tepig, we'll have a little place, and you'll get to tend the Pikachus...
Now I don't have a Pokémon! Can't travel!
And the Professor is gone...
Maybe I'll find something in her office.
There's a Poké Ball in the trash!
Who would throw away a Pokémon, unless it's...
No! Oh no, it's the Trash Pokémon!
It's a goddamn Eevee!
Reached (Accumula) Furret Town.
Time to head to the Poké Center.
Eevee only took 3 damage getting here, but it's so weak that it took forever.
This could not get any worse!
Wait, what did you say?
N-No, I don't have health insurance.
I owe you 500,000 Pokédollars?! For 3HP?!
"Did you forget where this game takes place?"
I guess I officially have motivation to become the Champion.
When we step out, we meet this game's villains.
Medieval animal rights activists!
Who want to liberate Pokémon from their enslavement.
Makes sense. Have you seen Mr. Mime?
That's a dude.
"My father had his speech in Furret Town."
"I only came here because I heard Wolfgang would be there."
"This, was a trainer, who as a mere child,"
"Poké battled the Pope."
"It could be anyone here."
"Even the, simple girl that did not look generic."
After battling a random creep, Cheren tells you:
To head to the first Gym in- stri-Stri- Striaton?
Let's do this!
"Welcome to - Striooition City Gym."
"Here, you will face the opposite of your starter!"
Um, m-my starter died...
(mumbling)
"Uhh, I'm so sorry!"
"Let me go talk to the guys,"
"Here. Have the badge! We're sorry for your loss."
I-It's fine.
"But guess what?"
W-What?
"The gym came together..."
O-Okay...
"To get you one of the most popular Pokémon there is!"
Oh no...
"We're giving you... an Eevoil!"
Do you mean 'Eevee'?
"It's pronounced 'Eevoi!'"
Goddammit, now I have two Eevees!
Speak.
'more oil!'
Huh!
Here, we head east, to a place with lots of oil drums..?
[Eevee noises]
Oh shit, one of my Eevoils has lost its (?)
Eevee evolved into Leafeon!
Team Wildlife fund charges me,
If animal rights activists wore armor...
...would they be taken more or less seriously?
Like, not officially, but in like bars.
No one's gonna argue with a vegan
who is wearing full plated armor.
This is... this is creepy. Fuck off.
Let's head west!
Two Team Plasma members stole this tiny girl's Pokémon.
They explain that they saw her attempt to light it on fire.
We don't care.
We're only loyal to the Pokédollar.
She says she can now finish the job.
How adorable!
After a short journey, we reach Nacrene-
(sees Cheren) Oh.
A nice town!
Has train tracks,
There's a nice cafe...
Close to Pokéhattan... (Castelia City)
All in all, I think this place might have the highest rent we've seen so far in the Pokémon universe.
The gym is in a museum-
(sees N) Ah no, not this dude!
N: Our first battle, must have been a fluke!
But her way with Pokémon...
The beginning, is simple.
Almost comic...
Just a, Tackle, that kills my Pokémon.
Switch! And suddenly,
another Tackle, until a Tackle takes over...
Sweetening to Tackles of such delight...
This was not battling by a performing Mankey...
This was battling I've never seen.
It was if to me...
I was seeing the drunken brawl of Arceus.
But WHY?!
Why would Arceus choose an obscene child to be his legendary hero?
The gym is a library.
You are supposed to find clues in books and-
I'm not gonna do this.
Torrenting, torrenting.
Ah, you solved my puzzle.
Nope, I ctrl+f'd some pdfs.
You can't do that, that's illegal!
I also illegally 3d printed the badge!
Before she can call her lawyers on me, Team Plosma steals a fossil head.
Why? Because Nick Cage once paid $300,000 for a dinosaur skull.
It's a way to get funding...
Wait. $300k? My debt! I gotta find it first! There's a chance I get to meet Nick Cage!
You'll never take this fossil from Team Plasma!
I'll give you $200,000.
Plasma shmasma am I right?
I'm a tiny girl. I can't carry a 300 kilo dino skull.
I'll just call him and see if he wants it.
Yeah. I want it! But I don't have the money
OH NO! NOT THE BEEDRILLS!
But I can send you...
My favorite pokemon...
(Kilian) It's a goddamn Eevee
What did that kid say before?
Setting fire to pokemon is fun?
Good thing yanks use gas stoves.
Ah goddammit
No not the fire one! He's gonna be a nightmare with entrance security!
Now that we arrive at our main destination...
Ladies and gentlemen...
The beautiful big flapple...
New Motostoke!
This isn't your nineties kids pokemon city...
This is a real city!
In shady alleys people give you
I'm guessing illegal moves.
No homeless people because
Crocodiles (Krookodiles) Eat them!
Help the gym leader with a shady drug deal!
The leader of team plasma say they intend to ask a dragon to change the world into their ideology...
Don't get high on your own supply!
The gym here is an insect-bee gym.
Gonna say what we're all thinking.
If there's a pokemon New York,
is there a pokemon Seinfeld?
And if so...
Is there a beedrill movie?
Explain that one.
WhAt?
Oh!
You don't know the plot of bee movie?
Well, let me explain it to you
(Explaining to him)
...and they fly off.
OH GOD
So what did you-
TAKE THE BADGE AND LEAVE
Did you li-
TAKE THE FUCKING BADGE AND NEVER RETURN
To get to the next city we need to cross the famous
New York
Desert.
While we walk professor Juniper calls us.
Hi kids!
Do any of you know a good divorce lawyer?
Uh
Don't say anything we'll talk about this in person.
Kids,
never trust a pokeball engineer.
They will try to catch anything.
After that we arrive in Nimbasa city.
Based on meat-town Manhattan.
Also called
"New York" in European
This town houses arenas you can preform in to get some debt money.
"This is Wolfgang!"
"She can battle like anyone!"
"Battle like red"
Okay
(Attacks water-rock type with fire-type move)
(Distorted Laughter)
"Now, battle like Brendan!"
Right
(Attacks water-rock type with grass-type move)
(Distorted Laughter)
Uh, another?
"Like Brock!"
I don't, I don't like him
N: Battle like N
Ah, now that's a challenge
"Hello pokemon i can talk to you I am creepy"
(Distorted laughter)
go ahead, mock me
laugh,
(Distorted laughter)
That as not Wolfgang laughing at me father,
That was ARCEUS (pronounced Arr-Keh-Yoos)
Arceus
What?
It's pronounced Ar-key-us
It's a god,
not a,
uh
dish soap.
after performing for a bunch of 17 hundreds people,
you're approached by that creepy green-haired guy
who tells you to ride the ferris wheel
worried he might go joker on me if I don't say yes
if he tries anything I'm going to jump
He tells me that he's the King of Team Plasma.
Then he says
"I wonder how many Pokemon
Arceus has blessed us with.
And you... are cho-
Blah blah blah blah blah,
was breast fed until I was twelve,
blah blah blah blah blah.
The local gym leader convinces Bianca's dad that letting a child out is good, because it removes weakness.
A dead child is better than a weak child.
Her gym is a electric gym...
with ????????????
roller coasters.
You could have just built bridges
there was no point such a huge amount of money
on theme park rides.
unless...
this is a money laundering scheme.
No, man fears rollercoaster,
destroyers of moral,
so if I report you to the internal revenue service,
I dropped the badge oh no
The gym leader has to open the golden gate bridge for us.
On our way we come across this regions champion.
Cheren asks him why a champion is standing here
hitting on clowns instead of doing something productive
I ask myself that everyday,
your words cut deep.
The fact that the gym leader can only open
and close the bridge when someone
defeats her must be really
devastating to the other sides economy.
Anyways, we leave the hot desert,
cross the bridge,
and end up in Alaska.
That bridge was 3 thousand kilometres long.
We are immediately introduced to this town's gym leader,
A completely generic american.
That's what all of them look like
Opening the bridge apparently lets team plasma escape
(I'm guessing from the death penalty...)
We only are allowed to challenge him if we find team plasma
It's like he always says...
The only person who can stop
a bad guy with the move water gun
is a good guy with the move water gun.
So I guess we need a water pokemon.
Hi guy who's wearing sunglasses and a suit
while selling potatoes
do you have any ?????????? fish?
Uhhhhh...
I'm pretty high...
eh but I think we have...
1 half of an alive fish...
Half alive fish?
What
Ah dammit!
Fortunately this time fish Eevee
is OP as
fuuuuuuuuuuck.
Team Plasma are hiding in a container in a cold storage.
Cheren suggests we just walk out and shut the door.
Let them freeze to death.